Register of the Arthur N. (Arthur Nichols) Young Papers, 1918-1982
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1919-1961. (Box 107-110)
  Reports, studies, ephemeral publications, and news clippings. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - China, 1919-61 (Box 107.)
    - Agriculture, 1928-60.
    - Communist China, general, 1945-60.
    - Culture and education, 1935-60.
    - Currency, 1926-35.
    - Customs, 1930-37.
    - Economic reconstruction, 1933-60
    - Finance, 1925-46. (Box 108.)
    - Japanese relations, 1919-38.
    - Law, 1945
    - Nationalist China, 1929-60.
    - Taiwan, 1951, 1951-61. (Box 109.)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations. Annual Reports, Conference Papers, and China Bibliography, 1938-60.
  - Office of the American Commercial Attache, Reports, 1932-37.
  - Office of the American Commercial Attache. Reports, 1932-37. (Box 110.)
  - Increment.
  - Oral History Interview with Dr. Arthur N. Young, Pasadena, California, February 21, 1974, by James R. Fuchs, Harry S. Truman Library. 1975., 157 p.
  - Banking from 7-7-37. (Box 111.)
  - Central Bank from 7-7-47.
  - Food situation, rice, 1946-
  - Graphs from 1937-1945-Prices, etc.
  - Graphs of finances, 1946.
  - Note issue from 7-7-37.
  - Silver and Coinage from 7-7-37.
  - Wartime statistics, misc. (largely prepared for [Laughlin] Currie).
  - Chinese finances, 1932. (Box 112.)
  - Oral History Interview (photocopy) Harry S. Truman Library, Independence, Missouri, August, 1975.
  - Printed material, 1928-1932.
  - Shanghai finances, 1946.
  - Silver, 1939-1943.
  - Silver and gold, July-December, 1938.
  - Silver sales, July, 1937-June, 1938.
  - Diary, 1929-1947 (incomplete). (Box 113.)
  - China
    - Commercial treaties
    - Communism
  - Report to the Prime Minister, Taiwan, 1958.
  - Russia - China relations, 1929-1935.
  - Yalta and its sequel, 1945-1951.
  - Chau, Yau Pik, The Taxation Reforms of the Chinese National Government in the Decade 1927-37, Doctoral Dissertation, University of Chicago, March, 1942. (Box 114.)
  - China (Box 115.)
    - Ministry of Finance
      - Reports
        - Chinese Budget Law, edited by Frederick A. Cleveland, n.d.
        - Estimates and Budget of the Inspectorate of Salt Revenue for the 19th Fiscal Year of the Chinese Republic, September 9, 1930.
        - Report on Personnel Administration, by Frederick A. Cleveland, 1934.
        - Statistical Review of the Work of the Inspectorate, 1913-1933, by Frederick A. Cleveland, 1934.
        - Annual Reports, 1930, 1931, 1932, 1934, 1935, 1937. (Box 116.)
        - German Reich's Budget Law of December 31, 1922, edited by Frederick A. Cleveland, 1931.
        - New Monetary Policy of China, The, Currency Reserve Board, Shanghai, January 15, 1936., (2 copies).
        - Problem of Putting the Principles of the New Salt Law into Effect The, by Frederick A. Cleveland, 1935.
        - Regulations Governing the Reich's Cash Offices, (Reichskassenordnung: R.K.O.) Promulgated 6th August, 1927, edited by Frederick A. Cleveland, 1931.
        - Statistical Review of the Work of the Inspectorate of Salt Revenue from 1913 to 1933 Inclusive, Digest of Facts and Statement of Conclusions Reached in Report, by Frederick A. Cleveland, 1934.
  - National Economic Council
    - Annual report, 1935.
    - Opening Address delivered at the First Meeting on November Fifteenth in the Twentieth Year of the Republic of China, 1931.
  - National Flood Relief Commission
    - Work of the National Flood Relief Commission of the National Government of China, The - August, 1931-June, 1932, Shanghai, June, 1932.
  - State Council
    - China's Economic Reform Plan, 1947.
    - Temporary Regulations with Regard to Foreign Exchange Transactions, Temporary Foreign Trade Regulations, February 25, 1946.
  - League of Nations
  - Council Committee of Technical Collaboration with China. Report to the Council of its Technical Delegate on his Mission in China from Date of Appointment until April 1, 1934.
  - Annexes to above, April, 1934.